(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-07T01:11:49.598098",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
静まり返り
Falling silent,
眠る街を駆けゆく
running through the sleeping town,
吹き抜け踊る
dancing in the wind,
風に乗り夜の淵へ
riding the wind to the edge of the night.
輝く月が その横顔を捉える
The shining moon catches your profile.
冷たく光る 左手は何を掴む
Shining coldly, what does your left hand grasp?
解れゆく世界の 欠片をひとひら
A single fragment of the unravelling world,
意志の火を片手に 翳り歩く
walking in the shadows with the fire of will in hand.
終わりなど見えない 仕組みなのだから
Because this is a system where no end is in sight,
問う事は諦め 一つ一つ
giving up on questioning, one by one.
糸茎途切れ 気付けば唯一の針
Threads cut off, before I knew it, the only needle
縋る事さえ 許されずに膝を折る
unable to even cling to it, I fall to my knees.
水面に映る ツギハギだらけの身体
Reflected on the water's surface, a patched-up body,
空蝉に問う これは夢か幻か
asking the empty shell: is this a dream or an illusion?
くたびれては眠り 赤い夢を見る
Growing weary, I fall asleep and see a red dream.
空蝉に問う
Asking the empty shell,
篝火は倒れて 空を焦がす
Bonfires collapse and scorch the sky.
責き立てられるように
As if being urged on,
泥裏に歩き出す
I step out into the mud.
孤独な太陽の様に 繰り返しで
Like a lonely sun, repeating endlessly...
繋ぎ止める 全ての火を
Binding and holding back all the flames...
澄み切った青空
A crystal-clear blue sky,
岩陰にもたれて
Leaning against the shade of a rock,
頬撫でてゆく風は「おやすみ」と呟いた
The wind caressing my cheeks whispered, "Good night."
ほつれ ほつれ 片手に戻る 現世の記憶は
Unraveling, returning to pieces, memories of this world are...
無残の瀬戸際を未だ見ず
Still unable to see the ruthless brink,
辛うじて留める形を繋ぐ 冴えない魔法は
Barely holding together its shape, this dull magic is...
掛け替えの無い命の影
The shadow of an irreplaceable life.
動かぬその右手には クチナシの花束を
In that motionless right hand, a bouquet of gardenias,
地に返る魂に捧ぐ 花向け
Offered as a farewell to the soul returning to earth.
残された世界には 朽ちなしの絶望と
In the world left behind, with unfading despair,
願わくば束の間の永遠を
I wish for a fleeting eternity.
昔々 あるところに とても素晴らしい魔法の王国がありました。
Once upon a time, in a certain place, there was a wondrous magical kingdom.
しかし、その王国は争い事に負けてしまい世界から消え、雪の中に埋もれてしまいました。
However, that kingdom lost a war, vanished from the world, and was buried deep in the snow.
それから数百 年、1人の白キツネの子がこの荒廃した地を訪れ、自分の国を作りたいと願いました。
Several hundred years later, a little white fox visited this desolate land and wished to build a country of her own.
争い事の無い輝かしい王国を もう一度…。
A brilliant kingdom free of conflict, once more...
吹きすさぶ風に舞う 光追いかけて
Chasing the light dancing in the howling wind,
辿り着いた昔の王都
I arrived at the ancient royal capital of the past.
吹き荒ぶ風に舞う、光追いかけて
Chasing the light dancing in the howling wind,
辿り着いた、昔の王国
I arrived at an ancient kingdom.
飛び交う竜の影が滑る大地を
Over the land where the shadows of soaring dragons glide,
「未来」で遺跡だった塔が見下ろす
a tower that became ruins in the "future" looks down.
幼い頃から好きな古書に
In the old book I loved since childhood,
書かれた伝承が私の目の前に広がる
the written legends unfold right before my eyes.
遥か彼方を往く翼に手を振る
Waving to the wings heading far into the distance,
空を映した瞳を見開く
I open wide my eyes reflecting the sky.
遠い景色に懐かしさを覚え
Feeling a sense of nostalgia in the distant scenery,
耳に蘇る歌を口ずさむ
I hum the song reviving in my ears.
澄み渡る湖に鱗が跳ねれば
When scales leap in the crystal-clear lake,
水泡が光を浴び煌めく
bubbles bathe in the light and shimmer.
振り向いた夕焼けに並んだ影は
The shadows lined up against the turning sunset
飛竜の形に造られた石像
are stone statues shaped like flying dragons.
禁忌を願った竜の運命
The fate of the dragon that wished for the taboo:
身体は石となり魂を閉じ込める
its body turned to stone, trapping its soul.
神の授けに私はただ震えて
To the divine decree, I could only tremble,
何もできずに唇を噛んだ
and bite my lips without being able to do anything.
指で触れても鉄のように冷たいだけで
Even when touched by fingers, it's as cold as iron,
届かない、竜の心に
unreachable to the dragon's heart.
悪しき予感が過る胸を誤魔化し
Shrugging off the premonition crossing my chest,
星を映した瞳を閉ざした
I closed my eyes reflecting the stars.
不意に零れたその涙の理由さえ知らず
Not even knowing the reason for the tears that suddenly fell,
陽は沈み大地は眠りに落ちる
the sun sets and the earth falls into slumber.
安らかに
Peacefully...
白キツネの子の歌の魔法が雪を溶かし、
The magic of the white fox child's song melted the snow,
その声に、夢に惹かれた者達が「一緒に」と手を差し出しました。
and those drawn to the voice and dream reached out their hands, saying "Together."
どんどん国に暖かな火が灯り始め、希望に溢れた街が生まれました。
Warm fires began to light up the land, giving birth to a town filled with hope.
その眩い光景に白いキツネの子は過去と、これからの未来に思いを馳せるのでした。
In that dazzling sight, the white fox child reflected on the past and the future to come.
本日はFBKINGDOM PROLOGUEにお越し下さり、ありがとうございますーー！
Thank you very much for coming to FBKINGDOM PROLOGUE today!
皆さん、見て下さい後ろー！
Everyone, look behind me!
なんかでっかいのが立ってるー！
There's something huge standing there!
もしやこれはFBKINGDOMのお城が…
Could this be FBKINGDOM's castle...
ちょっとずつちょっとずつ出来上がってってことー！
being built bit by bit, step by step?!
わーーい！
Yay!
ちょっと今までね、FBKINGDOM結構曖昧なところがあり、みんながダンボールに住んでたりなどなどしてきましたけども…
Up until now, FBKINGDOM has been a bit ambiguous, with everyone living in cardboard boxes and all that...
ついに今日、もしかすると立派なお城が立つのかなー？どうかなー？
but finally today, maybe a magnificent castle will stand? I wonder!
ここから始まるFBKINGDOM！ちょっと皆さんお楽しみにしてください！
FBKINGDOM starts right here! Everyone look forward to it!
そして、本日の生誕のハッシュタグなんですけども、皆さんFBKINGDOMプロローグとなっておりまーーす！
Also, today's birthday hashtag is... everyone, it's #FBKingdomPrologue!
カタカナと英語、どっちでもオッケーということで海外に行くは英語かなと思っております！
Katakana or English, both are fine, so for overseas fans I figured English might be good!
まずね、1曲2曲とちょっと続けてね、紙芝居なんかも挟みつつ楽しんでいただけましたでしょうか？
First off, having played a couple of songs and included a kamishibai, did you enjoy it?
ここからはね、ちょっとダンスとかめちゃめちゃ頑張りパートなので今から気合いを入れていこうと思います！
From here on, it's a super hard-working dance part, so I'm gonna get pumped up!
たくさんたくさんスクショとかね、ポストとかしてくださいね！よろしくお願いします！
Please take lots and lots of screenshots and make posts! Thank you!
では次の曲行ってみましょう！
Now let's move on to the next song!
宵の街 照らす灯火
Lights illuminating the twilight town,
高らかに 響く旋律
a melody echoing proudly.
月明かり 背に受けながら
With the moonlight at our backs,
ひとり 魔女は歌う
a lone witch sings.
少女は彷徨う 目的地見出せずに
A girl wanders, unable to find her destination,
杖を掲げたまま 見えぬ明日に向かって
holding her staff aloft, heading toward an unseen tomorrow.
鐘の音がこだましようとも
Even if the sound of the bell echoes,
この世界で 魔女にはなれない
she cannot become a witch in this world.
空を揺蕩う旋律
A melody drifting through the sky,
誓いさえ 風に吹かれて
even her oaths blown by the wind.
広場に繋がる路地裏
In the alleyways connecting to the square,
そびゆ時計台見上げて
looking up at the towering clock tower.
石畳 ひとり佇む
Standing alone on the cobblestones,
影を落とす少女
a girl casting a shadow.
自らの呪縛で 自ら飼い続ける
Bound by her own curses, keeping them alive herself.
例え手を差し伸べようと 解けはしないでしょう
Even if you reach out a hand, they likely won't untangle.
かつてある者の消滅で 国は滅びて
With the disappearance of someone from the past, the country perished,
物語を紐解こうとも
even if we try to unravel the story.
私はまだ 君に学べない
I still cannot learn from you.
望まれるように演じる 役割は日々揺らめいて
Acting as desired, roles swaying day by day.
願いと祈りのメモリア
A memoria of wishes and prayers.
鐘の音がこだましようとも
Even if the sound of the bell echoes,
この世界で 魔女にはなれない
she cannot become a witch in this world.
空を揺蕩う旋律
A melody drifting through the sky,
誓いさえ 風に吹かれて
even her oaths blown by the wind.
物語を紐解こうとも 私はまだ君にはなれない
Even if we try to unravel the story, I still cannot become you.
薄氷照らす朝日に 答えを探し旅立とう
Into the morning sun illuminating thin ice, let's set off in search of the answer.
さあさあ この指に止まれ
Now, now, catch on to this finger,
後悔 後にしてもしらないぞ
even if you regret it later, who knows?
音に呑まれて、歌って踊って満たすだけ
Enveloped in sound, just sing, dance, and fulfill!
パンパン手を打ち鳴らし
Clap, clap, beat time with your hands,
ソソソラシドんな五線譜も
even G-A-B-C-D musical staves,
音色を敷いて、今導き出すよ
laying down the tone, now leading the way.
さあさあ この指に止まれ
Now, now, catch on to this finger,
後悔 後にしてもしらないぞ
even if you regret it later, who knows?
音に呑まれて 歌って踊って満たすだけ
Enveloped in sound, just sing, dance, and fulfill!
パンパン手を打ち鳴らし
Clap, clap, beat time with your hands,
ソソソラシドんな五線譜も
even G-A-B-C-D musical staves,
音色を敷いて 今導き出すよ
laying down the tone, now leading the way.
招待は 実は案外 悲しいもの
The invitation is actually quite a painful thing,
魔法の音色 空に響かせて
let the magic's tone resonate to the sky,
おいでよ
Come on over!
街を包み込んだ 超常現象が
An extraordinary phenomenon wrapping around the town,
夜空に、ほらこだまして 退屈が泣き出す
echoing out into the night sky, boredom starts to cry,
孤独な愛を埋めよう 最終幻想的ノクターンが
the final delusional nocturne to bury lonely love.
君は聞こえた？ 星に舞う旋律を
Could you hear it? The melody dancing in the stars,
ワンツーさんしで泣いてた
crying with a one-two-three,
過去に負けない巡る力を
the strength to wander on without losing to the past,
たった楽しいリズムで 途切れない音を乗せて タッタン
with a cheerful rhythm and unending sound.
愛を画こうセプテット
Let's paint a world of love together,
忘れてた 景色の一番向こうのその向こう
beyond the scenery we had forgotten,
見て頂話のほころび モノクロの望遠鏡
seeing the chronicle of ruins through a monochrome telescope,
もっと私のぶつけ本番で
now it's time to put my real intention on stage!
奏でよう 理想描く 幻想的進行で
Play it out with an ideal, fantastic progression,
いつも目が合うアイツと 手を繋ぎ踊ろう
holding hands and dancing with the one whose eyes always meet yours,
何度も泣いてないた心のエレジーを
I heard the elegy of a heart that cried and wept again and again,
僕は聞こえた だから今ここにいるんだ
that's why I'm here right now.
招待は実は案外 悲しいもの
The invitation is actually quite a sorrowful thing,
魔法の音色 空に響かせて
let the magical tone echo through the skies,
おいでよ
Come on over!
街を包み込んだ 超常現象が
An extraordinary phenomenon wrapping around the town,
夜空に、ほらこだまして 退屈が泣き出す
echoing out into the night sky, boredom starts to cry,
愉快な歌を歌おう 最終演奏アンサンブルを
singing a joyful song, the final performance ensemble.
君は聞こえた？ 星に舞う旋律を
Could you hear it? The melody dancing in the stars,
ワンツーさんしで泣いてた
crying with a one-two-three,
過去に負けない巡る力を
the strength to wander on without losing to the past,
たった楽しいリズムで 途切れない音を乗せて タッタン
with a cheerful rhythm and unending sound.
パンパン手を打ち鳴らし
Beat, beat, tap your hands to the rhythm,
踊れ踊れ オーケストラ
dance, dance, orchestra,
バイバイ今夜はさようなら
bye-bye, tonight is goodbye,
次は君もステージで タッタン
next time you'll be on stage too!
さあさあ この指に止まれ
Now, now, catch on to this finger,
後悔 後にしてもしらないぞ
even if you regret it later, who knows?
justice is still in my heart 君に届け ユースティティア
Justice is still in my heart, reaching out to you, Justitia.
暗闇が立ち込めた様な 見捨てられた街で
In a city abandoned, as if swallowed by darkness,
暗闇が立ち込めた様な 見捨てられた街で 一人 孤独を謳う 君を見た
In a forsaken town wrapped in pitch darkness, I saw you singing of solitude all alone.
甦る過去に木霊して 君の腕を掴む ここが約束の地だと信じて
Echoing through awakened memories, I grab your arm, believing this is the promised land.
確かな答えは何処にも無いけれど 籠の中の小鳥は目覚めた
Though there is no certain answer anywhere, the small bird inside the cage has awakened.
羽根さえ無いまま 鼓動は加速して 僕らがこの日を この時を待ち続けてたんだ
Without even wings, my heartbeat accelerates—we have kept waiting for this day, for this time.
叶わぬ祈りに 救いの両手を 生まれ変われ 命のユースティティア
Offering saving hands to unfulfillable prayers, be reborn, Justitia of life.
どんな風吹いたって この声は消せやしない
No matter what wind is blowing, this voice cannot be erased.
明日の僕らに残せる物は何？ 宙を照らせ 一縷のユースティティア 秒だって狂わせない
What can we leave behind for our tomorrow? Illuminating the sky, a single thread of Justitia, not even a second will be thrown off.
奪われた世界を さあ 取り戻せ 重り合って いつの一日だって 僕らは共にいる
Take back the stolen world, come now. Overlapping, no matter what day it is, we are together.
錆び付いた扉に手掛けして 再び描く今 君の 君だけの物語が始まる
Placing a hand on a rusted door, drawing the present once more, your, only your story begins.
失くした言葉と言葉の意味を紡ぎ合わせて 強く 誰より力強く 咲き誇るその根を
Spinning together the meanings of lost words, stronger, more powerful than anyone else, those roots in full bloom...
どうか絶やさないで
Please do not let them wither.
僕が僕らしくあること 君が君らしくあること それが果てしない僕らのユースティティア
For me to be myself, for you to be yourself, that is our endless Justitia.
叶わぬ祈りに 救いの両手を 生まれ変われ 命のユースティティア
Offering saving hands to unfulfillable prayers, be reborn, Justitia of life.
どんな風吹いたって この声は消せやしない
No matter what wind is blowing, this voice cannot be erased.
明日の僕らに残せる物は何？ 宙を照らせ 一縷のユースティティア 秒だって狂わせない
What can we leave behind for our tomorrow? Illuminating the sky, a single thread of Justitia, not even a second will be thrown off.
奪われた世界を さあ 取り戻せ
Take back the stolen world, come now.
偽り合って 騙されたって それでもそっと 光は降って いつかはきっと 必ずきっと 僕が君の心 灯すから
Even if we deceived each other, even if we were tricked, even so, gently, light will fall down. Someday for sure, definitely for sure, because I will light up your heart.
特に何も望むことなんてない
There’s nothing I’m wishing for in particular...
身の程は知っているさ
I’m aware of what I’m capable of.
そんな僕でさえも奥の方に 譲りたくない意向程度はあるらしい
But despite all that, deep down, I seem to have a degree of intention to refuse to let go.
守るって案外と難しいね
Protecting something is more difficult than I'd expected.
諦めるわけじゃないけど
It's not like I'm just going to give up.
蒼い空の果て 繋がった道の行方
At the other side of the blue sky, the destination of these connected roads...
人と人は分かり合えない
People cannot understand one another,
だけどいいんじゃない
but that's alright!
開いた扉は全てを変えていく
The gate that opened up will change everything,
それは暁のように
just like the break of dawn!
何かを害することくらい
Anyone can cause harm to something,
誰にでも起こり得るだろう
right? That's bound to happen to anyone.
何かを愛することなんて
Loving something...
もっと単純な話だと思えてきたから
seems like a much simpler story than I thought,
自分に返ってくる対価を
so expecting returns
期待したりしない そんなのするだけ無駄さ
is a total waste of time.
重要なのはひとつ それをやりたいかどうかなんだ
The only thing that matters is whether you want to do it.
(ねぇ)だって君はここに一人しかいない
Because you're the only one here.
蒼い空の中 守るべきモノがある
There are things to protect in the blue sky,
それはどんな世界で生きるか より大切だから
which is more important than the world you live in.
開いた扉の先に何があっても
No matter what lies beyond the open gate,
迷ってしまわないように
so you won't get lost along the way.
大体の 場合偉い奴は 信用ならないけど
Most of the time, authority figures can't be trusted,
必要があるなら 仕方ないって 思えなくもない
but I can't help thinking it's fine if it's necessary.
ならやるべきことは 分かりきってるはずさ
Then you should already know what needs to be done.
それくらいのやる気はあるだろう？
You've got at least that much drive, right?
蒼い空が割れ 夢と現実が混ざる
The blue sky splits, and dreams mix with reality.
人と人は分かり合えない そんな場合じゃない
People can't understand each other—this isn't the time for that!
開いた扉は全てを変えていく
The gate that opened up will change everything,
それは暁のように
just like the break of dawn!
はい！ということで、皆さん新衣装です！
Yes! So everyone, this is the new outfit!
そしてそして！FBKキングダム完成です！
And and! The FBK Kingdom is complete!
すごい！立派なお城が、いよいよ我々のお家ができました！イェーイ！
Amazing! A splendid castle, our home is finally built! Yay!
そしてね、国旗をもおたためいておる！うおお！
And you see, we're even waving the national flag! Whoa!
よーちょっと、いいじゃないですか！王様らしくなりましたよね！ねえ！
Hey, isn't this great? I've really become like a king, right? Right?!
そしてゲストの皆とね、ま、ゲストと言うかもうこのスィオね一緒に作り上げてくれたホロメンたちとも一緒に歌いつつ、そしてね、ステージの前にいるストームのみんなの力でこんなに立派なお城ができました！
And with our guests—or rather, the holomembers who helped build this world with us—we sang together, and thanks to the fans in front of the stage, such a splendid castle was built!
そしてそして、ちょっと旗を置いとこうかな。
And, let me put down the flag for a bit.
えー、そしてこちら、えー衣装名はセイント衣装となっております。
Um, and this here, um, the outfit name is the Saint Outfit.
ちょっとみんなさんにじっくり見てもらいたいので、くるくるーっとね。
I want everyone to take a close look, so I'll spin around.
え、いろんなね、この頭の岡のところとかにも、なんとね、金木犀が回っておりまして、白上の大好きなお花の金木犀がもう本当にいーっぱい、いーっぱい入ってる衣装となっております！
Around the top of the head here, there are even osmanthus flowers spinning—Shirakami's favorite osmanthus flowers are packed so, so much into this outfit!
かわいい！
So cute!
え、そしてですね、なんとこの、えー衣装なんですけども、王冠が多分外れるのかな？王冠もトレちゃったのかな？どうだよ。
And also, for this outfit, I wonder if the crown comes off? Did the crown fall off too? What do you think?
いけますか？ほい！あ、取れた取れた。
Can we do it? Hop! Ah, it came off, it came off.
そして多分ね、マントもね、この、このケープもきっと消えるかな？どうかな？
And probably, um, the cape here will surely disappear too? I wonder?
きゃ、びっくりした！
Eek, you startled me!
あ、起きた！よかった～
Ah, you're awake! Yay~
こんな感じにちょっとね、ラフな格好にもなるんですね。
It can also look a bit casual like this.
わぁ～！
Wow~!
そしてこのふわふわの髪の毛！ふぁふぁふぁふぁ～！
And this fluffy hair! Fu-fa-fa-fa~!
良くないですか？これ。かわちい！
Isn't it nice? This. So cute!
とてもとても、えーかわいいお洋服を作っていただけました。ありがとうございます！
They made such a very, very cute outfit for me. Thank you very much!
そしてなんか後ろのこの石像！スコーン部に石像職人の方いらっしゃいました！なんかフブが要るんですよ！
And back there, this stone statue! There was a stone sculptor in the Skorn club! Somehow, Fubu is there!
なんかお前の白みたいになってるけど、違うからなお前！
It looks like my castle, but that's not you!
これは我々のお城だ！ね、フブじゃないですからね。
This is our castle! Hey, it's not Fubu, you know.
もう、わかってますか皆さん？
Come on, do you all understand?
ね、ちょっとスクショも撮ってもらおうかな。ピース！こう！ピース！
Hey, I'd like you to take some screenshots too. Peace! Like this! Peace!
いぇい！いぇい！いぇい！いぇい！いぇい！いぇい！いぇい！いぇい！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!
撮れるな、こんなにかわいい衣装！
Can you take it, such a cute costume!
ね、なんと、えーと色々これまでね、あのねアイドル衣装とかブルージャニーとかありましたけれども、白髪のこの単独の3D衣装というのは実は初めてですね、初めてなので
Hey, what's more, up until now there have been idol outfits, Blue Journey, etc., but this is actually the first time for Shirakami's solo 3D outfit, so since it's the first time...
すごいなんか、ね、緊張がすごいですけれども、きっとみんなね、すごい盛り上がってくれてありがとございまーす！ありがとうございます！
I'm really super nervous, but I'm sure everyone is super hyped, thank you so much! Thank you!
えーではですね、えーと衣装のお披露目もそこそこに、次の曲もいってみようと思います。
Um, so now, leaving the costume reveal aside for a bit, I'd like to try moving on to the next song.
さて、建国後のFBKINGDOM、まだまだこれからも続いていくぞー！
Now, FBKINGDOM after its founding will continue even further from now on~!
時は今！ようやく手にしたのは夢のぐだふわ生活！
The time is now! Finally, the dream of a lazy, fluffy life!
この愛しき日々を誰にも邪魔されずに満喫したい…
I want to fully enjoy these beloved days without anyone disturbing me...
ああそれなのに！立ちふさがるトラブル！またトラブル！
Ah, and yet! Standing in my way are troubles! More troubles!
だがそれでも諦めない！夢に描いた悠々自適生活を取り戻すまでは！
But even so, I won't give up! Until I reclaim the carefree life I dreamed of!
ぐだふわエブリデー
Gudafuwa Everyday
ぐだぐだぐだしていたいの 全人類共通項
Wanting to laze around is humanity's common trait.
食う 寝る あと何だっけ？？
Eat, sleep... what was the other one again??
あーあ 聞こえないです
Ah-ah, I can't hear you!
ヤダヤダもう邪魔しないで とっておきスローライフ
No way, don't bother me anymore! My precious slow life.
やりたいことだけ やって生きてたいわ
I just want to live doing only what I want to do.
しかし穏やかな生活を目指そうとしてもまるで荒波のように次々と困難は襲いかかってくるのです！
But even when aiming for a peaceful life, hardships come crashing down one after another like rough waves!
静謐 太平 我が家の安寧
Serenity, peace, and the safety of our home.
兎にも角にも 安らぎ重視で 平穏無事に 暮らしたい！
Above all, prioritizing peace of mind, I want to live safely and soundly!
叶えて私の Happy Days
Grant my Happy Days!
おはようからおやすみまでまるっと穏便に
From good morning to good night, completely peacefully.
余裕しゃくしゃく 釈子もネコも
Full of composure, both Buddhas and cats alike.
ふわふわ Why don't you そんな every day
Fluffy, why don't you have such an everyday?
晴耕雨読で 心穏やかな暮らし
Working in the fields in fair weather and reading in the rain, a peaceful life.
きっと手に入れてみせるわ！
I will definitely make it mine!
まだまだ足りないの 健康的市民生活
Still not enough, a healthy civic life.
ビタミン ミネラル 精神的サプリメント
Vitamins, minerals, and mental supplements.
クラクラしちゃうこのクライシス ラクラクに変えるそんな逆転劇 絶賛進行中
This dizzying crisis turned easily into a comeback story, currently in progress!
ぐだぐだするためにアクセクしなきゃいけないのってこれ本末転倒になっちゃってません？
Having to rush around just to laze about—isn't that putting the cart before the horse?
あ、これ気付いちゃダメなやつでした？
Ah, was this something I shouldn't have noticed?
気付かなかったことにしておきます！
I'll just pretend I didn't notice!
賢いことに越したことないけど
It's better to be wise, but...
いつの時代も変わらないもの 寝ても覚めても癒されたい！
What never changes in any era: wanting to be healed whether sleeping or waking!
許して不純な Ambitious
Forgive my impure Ambitious!
健康で文化的な最高限度のユートピア
A healthy and cultural utmost Utopia.
海鮮山鮮 ぬかりありません
Seafood and mountain food, no omissions!
ぐだぐだ Good な days 欲しいから
Because I want lazy, good days,
完全無欠で満ち足りた毎日を お星様にお祈りしよう
Let's pray to the stars for flawless, fulfilling days.
ぐだぐだふわ ぐだぐだふわり…
Gudafuwa, gudafuwari...
叶えて私の Happy Days
Grant my Happy Days!
揺り籠から墓場まで健やかに
Healthily from cradle to grave!
青息吐息 生きてゆくこと
Sighing and gasping as I live my life,
決して楽じゃないけれど
it's never easy, yet...
叶えて私の Happy Days
Grant my Happy Days,
おはようからおやすみまでまるっと
from morning until night, completely at ease.
穏に余裕しゃくしゃくシャキもネコも
Calm and utterly unbothered, both dogs and cats—
ふわふわ Why don't you そんな every day
fluffy, why don't you have such an everyday?
晴耕雨読で心穏やかな暮らし
Living a peaceful life of farming in the sun and reading in the rain,
手に入れるその日まで！
until the day I finally make it mine!
月夜のセレナーデ
Moonlight serenade,
白い薔薇は誰を想う
who does the white rose yearn for?
その身を震わせて
Trembling in body,
愛を歌うの
singing of love.
こぼれ落ちた花びらが
The fallen petals
寂しさの跡を隠した
concealed the traces of loneliness.
ねえ早く迎えに来て
Hey, come meet me quickly,
最後のひとひらが落ちるその前に
before the last petal falls.
今はどんな花とも群れないの
Now I won't flock with any other flowers;
あなただけを待ってる
I am waiting only for you.
あなたとならこの体が壊されたって構わない
If it's with you, I wouldn't care even if this body were broken.
棘に触れたら傷つくわ その覚悟がないなら
Touching thorns will hurt—if you don't have that resolve,
いっそここから消えてよ 重く閉ざした Secret Garden
then disappear from here at once! The heavily sealed Secret Garden.
夜風はリゾルート
The night breeze is resolute,
白い薔薇は覚醒する
the white rose awakens.
背中押されるように
As if pushed from behind,
扉開いた
the door opened.
ただ独りで枯れてゆくの？
Am I just going to wither away all alone?
待ってるだけじゃいられない
I can't just keep waiting.
衝動の赴くまま
Following my impulses,
茨の道を裸足で駆け抜けてく
I run barefoot down the path of thorns.
凛と咲き誇る華でありたい
I want to be a flower blooming proudly.
あなただけを求めて
Desiring only you,
逢いにゆくの
I am going to meet you.
どんな遠く離れていても見つけ出せる
No matter how far apart we are, I can find you.
暗い世界も怖くない あなたを感じるから
Even a dark world is not scary, because I feel you.
全て失ったっていい 二度と戻らない そう Secret Garden
It's fine if I lose everything, never to return—yes, a Secret Garden.
今はどんな花とも群れないの
Now I won't flock with any other flowers;
あなただけを求めて
desiring only you,
霞の向こう わたしを呼ぶ
calling out to me beyond the haze.
鮮やかに燃える強き薔薇
A fiercely burning, vibrant rose.
凛と咲き誇る華でありたい
I want to be a flower blooming proudly,
やっとここで出逢えた
having finally met you here.
あなたとならこの体が壊されたって構わない
If it's with you, I wouldn't care even if this body were broken.
棘に触れたら傷つくわ その覚悟があるのね
Touching thorns will hurt—you have that resolve, don't you?
手を取り合えばひろがる誰も知らない そう Sacred Universe
If we take each other's hands, it spreads outward into an unknown world—yes, a Sacred Universe.
間違っていないか、その再現性も関係を
Is there no mistake in its reproducibility or relationship?
そうとっても何か役に立つのか？
Even if so, does it serve any purpose?
夢なんか見ないで戦争をしようよ
Let's not dream and instead wage war.
瞑想も読経も笑って嘆き合う者
Meditating, chanting, and weeping together—
アンティークとなったキューブ製禁書
An antique, cube-shaped forbidden book's
概用の8128項の内容
contents under outline section 8128—
千変も時間も空間も内包
encompassing countless forms, time, and space—
信仰と祈り其の教理救い出すもの
faith and prayer, their doctrine, bringing salvation—
光よ 慈しみよ 深き
Oh light, oh mercy, deep...
尊き 汝の愛で
...and noble, with your love,
導き給え
guide us.
穿たれた福音 下された御指
A pierced gospel, a lowered finger,
焚べた崇高に灰になった権力者
The powerful reduced to ash upon the burning height.
消え去っていく論理 知れば戻れぬ昨日にその量子 悪を焼き去った
Fading logic, into a yesterday we can't return to, its quantum burned away evil.
剣よ 焼かれた元老院 裸に剥かれた武器商人
Swords, the burned senate, the stripped arms merchant,
鏖殺 苛烈さを増す学生達のテロ行為
Massacre, escalating brutality of students' terrorist acts.
上から見ればゲエンナ 下から観ればホザナ
Seen from above, Gehenna; seen from below, Hosanna.
嗚呼 こんな筈じゃなかった
Ah, it wasn't supposed to be like this.
奇蹟よ 思召しよ 人を
Oh miracle, oh divine will, mankind...
気高き 窮理の船に乗せ 導き給え
...upon the ship of ultimate reason and guide them!
導き給え
Guide us.
つまんない
Boring.
Da-da-du-la-da-da-du-la 現金はベストフレンド
Da-da-du-la-da-da-du-la, cash is your best friend!
あれもmoney これもmoney 多重債務の豚にゃ用なし
This is money, that is money, no use for multiple-debt pigs.
この先じゃハートはpricey 哀れ口先だけの貧乏人もノーチャンス
Ahead, hearts are pricey; pitiful, all-talk poor folks have zero chance.
それにready 引き換えlady 高貴な死の香りお纏いで
Ready for it? In exchange, lady, draped in the noble scent of death—
ソコに魂をお持ちなら望みを何なりと ハーマジェスティ
If you bring your soul there, whatever your wish may be, Her Majesty—
お迎えだ 絢爛に "ショータイム"
welcomes you lavishly to the 'Showtime'.
（絶対公平取引）
(Absolute fair trade)
（魂売ったり買ったり）
(Selling and buying souls)
（願ったりそして叶ったり）
(Hoped for and then granted)
（奪ったりもっと奪われたり）
(Stolen and stolen even more)
欲しいもの欲しいまま ゼンプ？ ゼンプ！
Whatever you want, just as you want—all of it? All of it!
さあ！ welcome to―― 豪華なドレス 淫靡なリップ 貴女の地獄へ クラブ＝マジェスティ
Now! Welcome to―― gorgeous dresses, alluring lips, to your hell, Club=Majesty!
歓迎さ強欲の君 私は召使どうぞ総統も 神様も
Welcome, greedy ruler; I am your servant, please, supreme leader and gods alike—
剥ぎなり 吊るなり 思い通り ご命令はなぁに？
strip them, hang them, just as you like. What is your command?
Da-da-du-la-da-da-du-la 現金はベストフレンド
Da-da-du-la-da-da-du-la, cash is your best friend.
お星様望むだけ降り注ぐ銀貨に囲まれて 家族は幸せに暮らしました――
Surrounded by silver coins raining down as the stars desire, the family lived happily ever after――
またのご冗談ばかり
Just another joke of yours.
逃げやしない！
You won't get away!
それがマネー 誰のマネー？
That's money, whose money?
百倍＆複利グレイト！
100x & compound interest, great!
借りたら返すのが正義でしょ？
Returning what you borrowed is justice, right?
魂売ったり買ったりの
Buying and selling souls,
Oh Shake it up!
本日もよろずご案内は内緒よ
Today's general guide is a secret, okay?
公平じゃない？
Isn't it fair?
魂売ったり買ったりの
Buying and selling souls,
願ったり叶ったりの
Wishing and having wishes granted,
奪ったり奪われたりの
Taking and being taken,
止められない
There's no stopping it.
モット？モット？モット？もっと！
More? More? More? More!
目覚めて煌めく 奈落の聖域 クラブマジェスティ
Awaken and sparkle, sanctuary of the abyss, Club Majesty!
絶望？絶望？どこから湧きましょう
Despair? Despair? Where shall it well up from?
弱虫なきまし隠してあげる
Hiding your cowardly tears,
どっとかせぎあいぜんぜんオーライ！
Earning in heaps, all right!
Da- Da- Da- Da- Da- Da- Da-ula... キャッシュはホワイトナイト
Da-Da-Da... Cash is White Knight!
(間奏)
(Instrumental Break)
絶賛ご好評お取引
Raving popularity, doing business!
魂売ったり買ったりの
Buying and selling souls,
願ったり叶ったりの
Wishing and having wishes granted,
奪ったり奪われたりの
Taking and being taken,
足りない？贅沢？
Not enough? Extravagant?
チョット？チョット？モット？モット？ゼンブ？オーライ！
Chotto? Chotto? Motto? Motto? Zenbu? All right!
もしかして愛だとか情だとかとワクな生体身につけてらっしゃるシダバシャ裏切らないのはやっぱり金でしょ？
Perhaps believing in love or affection as living creatures... what never betrays is money, right?
服装も お喋りも 生まれ立っちまえば命じゃないのさ
Outfits, small talk, once you're born, aren't they life?
痛い痛いな荒々しみを慈しみを あなたの血が騒ぐ プラウマジェスティ
Painful, painful roughness, cherish it, your blood stirs, Prowl Majesty!
青い青い豊かになれる煩悩エデュケーション 心ゆくまでお楽しみいただけましたの？キャッシュは失わないの
Blue, worldly desires education making you rich, did you enjoy it? Cash is not lost!
Da- Da- Da- Da- Da- Da- Da-ula...
一緒にしょ？ショット？ショット？
Isn't it together? Shot? Shot?
Da- Da- Da- Da- Da- Da- Da-ula...
キャッシュはペソプレン
Cash is Peso plane!
(間奏)
(Musical Transition)
きらりと輝く言葉 僕は探し続けた
Brilliant words that shine, I searched for them continuously,
色褪せる時間にさえ 気づかないでいた
Not even noticing the time as it faded away.
流れゆく星のように この夜空を翔べたなら
If I could fly through this night sky like a shooting star,
君に伝えたい声も 輝けるのかな
I wonder if the voice I want to convey to you would shine too.
掴んだヒカリ 解き放つオト 魔法をかけてよ
The light I've grasped, the sound I've released, cast a spell on me—
METEOR
この空を あの星を 奇跡さえ超えて君の元へ繋げるよ その夢を
This sky, those stars, going even beyond miracles, I'll connect them to your side, that dream—
最後まで離さないで
Never let it go until the very end.
この歌を この声を ずっと忘れないでいてね
This song, this voice, please never forget them.
届けたい 終わりのない空を 翔ける星のメロディ
I want to deliver the melody of stars flying through an endless sky.
(間奏)
(Instrumental Interlude)
きらりと果てのない道を 照らしてくスターライト
Starlight illuminating an endless, glittering path,
何も見えないけれど 僕は進んでゆく
Even though I see nothing, I will keep moving forward.
透き通る風のように この夜空を翔べたなら
If I could fly through this night sky like the clear wind,
砂にまみれた声も また光れるのかな
I wonder if my voice, stained with sand, could shine once more.
口ずさんだ そのメロディに 魔法をかけてよ METEOR
Cast a spell on the melody I hummed, METEOR!
君の書くその歌は 無数の光る言葉となって
The song you write becomes countless shining words,
目を覚ますこの声と シグナルが青に染まる
Awakening this voice, and the signal is dyed in blue.
これからも この先も 僕は君を振り返らせる
From now on and into the future, I'll make you look back at me.
笑って 笑って 飛ばせ笑顔 咲ける明日へ
Laughing, laughing, let your smile fly toward a blooming tomorrow!
願いを託す時間を止めてよ 鳴り止まない鼓動ハイスピード 無限に続くような銀河さえ 魔法に溶けてく
Stop the time in which we entrusted our wishes, an incessant heartbeat, high speed, even an infinite galaxy dissolves into magic.
ココロの中に星を降らせるよ
I'll make stars rain down in your heart,
しっかりと受け止めて欲しいんだ
hoping you'll catch them firmly.
君に伝えたいこの歌を今
This song I want to convey to you now
全力で歌っているから
is being sung with all my might.
この空を あの星を
This sky, those stars,
奇跡さえ超えて 君の元へ
going even beyond miracles, to your side—
飛べるよ どこまでも
I can fly, no matter how far.
今ならきっと大丈夫
If it's now, I'm sure it'll be fine.
この歌は この声は
This song, this voice,
いつも君の隣にある
is always right beside you.
届けたい 終わりのない空を
I want to reach the endless sky,
駆ける 星のメロディ
running with the melody of the stars.
巡り会う この場所で
In this place where we met,
君とふたりの夜空を見る
looking at the night sky together with you.
駆け出して 届けだって
Sprinting forth, hoping it reaches you,
きっと夢を 叶えるから
I will surely make our dreams come true.
この歌を この声を
This song, this voice,
ずっと忘れないでいてね
please never forget it.
届けたい 遥か遠い未来
I want to reach a distant, far-off future,
駆ける 駆ける 全速力のメロディ
running, running at full speed with this melody!
はい、ということでMETEOR聴いていただきましてありがとうございました！
Yes, so you listened to "METEOR", thank you very much!
いやあ、よかったあ！ふうー。
Phew, I'm so glad! Phew.
いやあ、今回の曲ね、ちょっとゆったりから始まり、ええ。
Well, this time's song started out quite relaxed, yeah.
なかなか激しい曲と来て、そして高い曲とね、後半になるにつれちょっとあの激しい感じにはなってってるんですけどもね。
It started with a pretty intense song, then high-pitched ones, and as it goes into the second half, it gets a bit more intense.
今回のちょっと曲順とか、あの、なんでこういうセットリストなのかってのはまたあの、後日お話しできたらと思います。
I hope to talk another day about the song order and why this setlist was chosen.
そして、なんと後ろ、なんかおるんですけど、え！
And look behind me, there's something there, huh?!
ふぶら、ちょっと、お前侵略しに来たのか？
Fubula, did you come to invade?
違うのか、守護神ってこと？フブキングダムの。そうなのかな？ええ？
Is that wrong? Are you the guardian deity of Fubukingdom? Is that it? Eh?
ちょっとあの、スコンブの中のあの、国民の皆さんと、あの、フブらシーク係募集しております。
Um, among the Sukonbu, we're recruiting people in charge of the Fubula secret guard from among the citizens.
あの、よろしくお願いいたします。ふうー。
Um, please treat us well. Phew.
ではですね、ここからは告知を二つちょっと、やっていこうかなと思います。ではでは、ふうー。
Now then, from here on, I'd like to make two announcements. Now then, phew.
まず一つ目は、こちら！白上フブキ誕生日記念2024グッズです！わあー！
First off, is this! Shirakami Fubuki Birthday Anniversary 2024 Goods! Wow!
ではではでは、早速どんなグッズがあるのか見ていきましょう。まず一つ目は、こちら！
Now then, let's go ahead and see what kind of goods there are. First off, this one!
タイトルがかっこいいすぎる、『黄昏の王』アクリルスタンドです！
The title is so cool, the "Twilight King" Acrylic Stand!
今回ね、さっきあの衣装の見てもらった時にこちらの衣装聖イント衣装って紹介したんですけども、実は今回のこのグッズのイラストを担当してくださっているゲゼルン先生がこちらの衣装のデザインもしてくださいました。
Geserun-sensei, who designed the illustration for these goods, also designed this outfit.
本当によし、本当にいつもありがとうございます！そんなゲゼルン先生、やっぱね、やっぱりもう衣装詳しいので、今回のグッズもおねがいしますとおねがいして描いていただきました！黄昏の王ということで、背景のスタンドグラスとかもフブキングダムをイメージして作っていただきました。とってもとっても可愛いアクリルスタンドです！
As the "Twilight King", the background stained glass and such were made imagining Fubukingdom. It's a very, very cute acrylic stand!
では続いては、こちら！缶バッジ！もうね、お顔が本当に、本当にかわちかわちなので、缶バッジもお願いさせていただきました！こちらはなんとですね、あのジュエリーホックというですね、ぷっくり立体な、なんとですね箱押しがついているんですよ！もうね高級感も抜群なので、ぜひぜひおしバッジ作ってくれると嬉しいです。
Now next is this! Can badge! It has a superb sense of luxury, so I'd be super happy if you make oshi badges with it.
では続いては、こちら！わあ、きーちゃん！スコンブ、あの、個人的に推しの犬を作るんですけども、その時にもいつも作っているお顔があるんですけど、そのお顔でなんと今回縫いを作っちゃいました！スコンブファクトリーVol.1 セイントフブちゃんぬいぐるみ！
Now next is this! Wow, Kii-chan! Sukonbu Factory Vol.1 Saint Fubu-chan Plushie!
はーい！ふぶきです！ふーー！
Hi! I'm Fubuki! Woo!
もうね、これボリューム1ということはもしや今後も作っていけるのかなという期待を込めてボリューム1にさせていただきました。
Since this is Volume 1, I made it Volume 1 in hopes we can make even more in the future.
ねえ、こちらのお顔でね、今後もなんか作っていけたらいいな。ぜひぜひ白上デザインさせていただいた、ぬいを運営さんが本当に良い感じにしてくださったぬいとなっておりますのでお迎えよろしくお願いします。
I hope we can make more with this cute face. Shirakami designed it, and management did a wonderful job making it, so I hope you'll welcome one home!
そして続いては、こちら！てーん！ふぶきダム勲章ピンバッチ！イェーイ！
And next is this! Tada! Fubuki Kingdom Medal Pin Badge! Yay!
この勲章をどうしてもグッズにしたかった。前にね、あの出したのふぶちゃおフェアのねあのバッグにもあの、この勲章のチャームがついてるんですけども、もっともっと大きくね、みんなにつけてほしいということで、こちらのね、勲章ピンバッチ作らせていただきました。
I really wanted to turn this medal into merch! The Fubuchao Fair bags had a medal charm, but I wanted a bigger one for everyone to wear, so we made this medal pin badge!
お洋服にねもちろんつけるのもいいんですけども、カバンとかねつけて一緒にいくことね、あの国民アピールをしていただければと思います。よろしくお願いします。
Of course you can wear it on your clothes, but you can also put it on your bag to show off your citizenship when you go out. I hope you'll get one!
そして、フルセット購入特典もございまーす！こちらのポストカードでーす！数量限定バージョン。直筆サインもございます。年に1回の直筆サイン、頑張りと、頑張りと思いますってなんだ、頑張ろうとも思います。
And we also have a full-set purchase bonus! This postcard! Limited quantity version, featuring a hand-written signature. Once a year hand-written signature, I'll do my best—wait, I'll work hard on it!
おっと、口が回んないや。頑張りますので、ぜひぜひ皆さんよろしくお願いいたします！
Oops, tongue tied. I'll do my best, so please everyone look forward to it!
さらに、フルセット特典として、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚付いてきまーす！こちらもよろしくお願いしますよ。
Plus, as a full-set bonus, you'll get one card usable in the Hololive Official Card Game! Please look forward to that too!
このあとカードオープンでーす！わーーーい！
We'll be opening cards right after this! Yayyy!
ということでね、今回はね、あの本当にいろいろ考えてグッズえ、出させていただきました。運営さんに気軽に気軽にというかこれでお願いします、これでおいますとね、言ってデザインこんなのですとかね、本当になんがいっぱい相談に乗っていただきありがとうございました。
So yeah, for this time we put a lot of thought into the merch. I told management "Please do it like this" and "Please do it like that", and they gave me so much advice on the design. Thank you so much.
スコンブファクトリーの工場で働いてるスコンブの皆さんはね、あの生産頑張ってください。よろしくお願いします。
To all the Sukonbus working at the Sukonbu Factory, please work hard on production! Please treat me well.
そして、告知2つ目！なんとこのあと、え、歌う楽曲新曲です！わあーーー！
And announcement number two! The song we're singing right after this is a brand new song! Wowww!
もうねレターに続くもう、新曲も白神の楽曲って本当にレターがめちゃめちゃもう、うわあもう白神って感じの曲なんですけども、
Following "Letter", this new song really gives off that classic Shirakami vibe—
このね、次歌わせていただく楽曲スーパノーヴァという楽曲なんですけども、またね、レターとは違ったあの、白神とスコンブの関係というか、ね、もうさらに、さらに、さらに盛り上がる、え、楽曲となっております！ちょっとね、みんな初見なのでね、いきなりね、合いの手とか難しいとは思うんですけども、覚えてね、またいつかね、こういうライブやる時に、イェーイ！イェーイ！って盛り上がってくれると嬉しいなっていう、そういう一緒に、本当に一緒に盛り上がれる楽曲となっておりますので、ぜひぜひ聴いてください。
And the next song I'll be singing is called "SUPERNOVA". It's a bit different from "Letter", showing the relationship between Shirakami and Sukonbu. It's an even more hype song! Since everyone's hearing it for the first time, chiming in with cheers might be tough, but if you memorize it and cheer along with "Yay! Yay!" when we do a live show someday, I'd be so happy. It's a song we can truly get hyped together on, so please give it a listen!
そして、この配信後にMVも公開します！楽しみにしててくださいね。よし。
And after this stream, the MV will also premiere! Please look forward to it. Alright.
よしよし、それでは聞いてください。「SUPERNOVA」
Alright, please listen. "SUPERNOVA".
甘くほろ苦い夢
A sweet and bittersweet dream,
“これでいいか” “これがいいか”
"Is this fine?" "Is this what you want?"
折れかけたあの日
On that day when I almost broke,
ここに間違いはなくて
There were no mistakes here,
正解もなくて自分次第で
No right answer, it's all up to me,
怖くて仕方ないけど
Even though I'm endlessly scared,
“誰か”じゃない“君”と見たい景色は鮮明で…
The scenery I want to see with "you", not just anyone, is vivid...
それじゃあ、ここで足踏みなんかしていられないじゃん！
So there's no way we can just stand still here!
Oh Yeah!! 無数の星の中 光は君がくれた
Oh Yeah!! Among countless stars, you gave me this light.
もっと！ 超えてゆけるさ
Even further! We can surpass it.
SUPERNOVA 超せ今！
SUPERNOVA, transcend it now!
何度だって跳べる
We can soar as many times as it takes.
これが紛れもない僕らの奇跡 Hi Friends!!
This is undoubtedly our miracle, Hi Friends!!
心、泣きじゃくる日でも
Even on days when my heart breaks into sobs,
いつだってここにいて？
Will you always be right here?
強がりはらしくないよ！
Putting up a front isn't like you!
“ひとり”じゃない “君”もほら 僕等、手取り合って
You're not "alone," look, we're holding hands together
笑おう！叫ぼう！あの宇宙の向こうへ
Let's laugh! Let's shout! To the other side of that universe!
Oh Yeah!! 無数の星の中 交わした約束も
Oh Yeah!! Even the promises we made among countless stars
きっと叶えられるさ！
will surely come true!
Oh Yeah!! SUPERNOVA 駆けろ、今！
Oh Yeah!! Run through, SUPERNOVA, now!
Oh Yeah!! 誰一人欠かせない
Oh Yeah!! Not a single person can be missing
あの日描いた夢の先まで Hi Friends!!
To the beyond of the dream we drew that day, Hi Friends!!
こんな現在を愛せるように
So that I can love this present moment,
君に向けて唄おう 心が叫んでる！
I will sing to you, my heart is crying out!
Oh Yeah!! 無数の星の中 光は君がくれた
Oh Yeah!! In the midst of countless stars, the light was given by you
もっと！越えていけるさ！
More! We can overcome it!
Oh Yeah!! SUPERNOVA 起こせ、今！
Oh Yeah!! Cause a SUPERNOVA, now!
Oh Yeah!! 何度だって翔べる
Oh Yeah!! We can fly no matter how many times
これは紛れもなく僕らの軌跡
This is undoubtedly our trajectory
“普通”も“あたりまえ”も無い 君が君らしく居れるように
So that with no "ordinary" or "taken for granted," you can be truly yourself
もっと！ずっと！届けよう遠くまで
More! Always! Let's deliver it far away
不思議と怖くはないんだ 綺麗事、絵空事でもない
Strangely, I'm not scared, it's neither pretty talk nor an illusion
さあ、行こう！この物語は終わらない！
Now, let's go! This story will never end!
白いキツネの子は手をかかげ歌い、その歌声が広場に響き渡ると、
The little white fox raised her hand and sang, and when her song echoed across the plaza,
人々の心は希望に満ち溢れ、1人、また1人と歌声が響き渡り
the people's hearts overflowed with hope, and one by one, voices joined in song,
街は光に包まれました。そしてついに…
and the town was enveloped in light. And finally...
白いキツネの子の夢は現実となり平和な王国は遥か未来まで続いていくのでした。
the little white fox's dream became reality, and the peaceful kingdom would continue far into the future.
めでたし、めでたし。
And they lived happily ever after.
君が居てくれるおかげで これまで頑張ってこれたよ
Thanks to you being here with me, I've been able to do my best until now
そんな君とこれから先も この場所を守っていきたい
I want to keep protecting this place with you from now on as well
心からのありがとうと
With heartfelt gratitude,
そして
and
100万回の愛してるを届けます
I send you a million 'I love you's.
フブキングダムとみんなに 祝福を込めて…
With blessings for FBKINGDOM and everyone...
国民の皆様、大変お待たせいたしました！
Citizens of the kingdom, thank you so much for waiting!
白上フブキファーストアルバム、「FBKINGDOM" Blessing"」の発売が来年1月15日に決定いたしましたー！
My 1st album, Shirakami Fubuki's "FBKINGDOM Blessing," is officially releasing on January 15th next year!
「FBKINGDOM」をコンセプトに、ファーストシングル「Say Fanfare!」など既存曲5曲に加え、新曲をなんと9曲新たに収録しております！
Centered around the concept of "FBKINGDOM," it features 5 existing tracks like my first single "Say Fanfare!" plus 9 brand-new songs!
DECO*27さん、藤田竜太郎さん、小池竜暉さん、久保直樹さんら豪華楽曲陣の皆様にアルバムに向けた新曲を書き下ろしていただきました！
Amazing composers like DECO*27, Ryutaro Fujita, Ryuki Koike, and Naoki Kubo have written brand-new tracks for this album!
ポップ、ロック、バラード、ファンタジックなものまで様々な曲に挑戦してますので、ぜひ今からどんなアルバムになるか楽しみにしていてくださいね！
From pop, rock, and ballads to fantastical tunes, I've challenged myself with all sorts of songs, so please look forward to what kind of album it'll be!
アルバムのイラストはナリロー先生に描いていただきました！このキング白上う〜、かわちい！皆さんもぜひお手にとってじっくり見てくださいね！
The album illustrations were drawn by Nariro-sensei! This King Shirakami is so-o cute! Everyone, please grab a copy and check out all the details!
そして今回、数量限定版もご用意！数量限定版は特別ワンピースボックス仕様となっており、
And this time, we also have a quantity-limited edition available! The limited edition comes in a special one-piece box,
CDジャケットの表情はニッコリ笑顔の表情差分イラスト！このジャケットは、こちらの数量限定版オリジナルバージョンとなっております！
and the CD jacket features an alternate smiling expression! This jacket is exclusive to this quantity-limited version!
封入特典としてアクリルスタンド、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームのPRカード、さらに！このジャケットイラストで白上が手に持っているFBKINGDOMからの招待状が入っております！
Bonus items include an acrylic stand, a Hololive Official Card Game PR card, and what's more! An invitation from FBKINGDOM that Shirakami is holding in this jacket illustration!
何が書かれているかは、届いてからのお楽しみ！数量限定版は本日このあと21時30分からホロライブオフィシャルショップにて先着順でご購入いただけます！
What's written inside is a surprise for when it arrives! The limited-edition version will be available on a first-come, first-served basis at the Hololive Official Shop at 9:30 PM today!
さらにさらにすごい！通常版は全国のCDショップでの販売が決定じゃー！ありがとうございます！
And even better! The regular edition has been confirmed for sale at CD shops nationwide! Thank you so much!
それぞれのCDショップにて購入者特典がついてきます！たくさん種類があるので迷ってしまうかもしれませんが、ぜひいろんなCDショップページをチェックしてみてくださいね！
Each CD shop comes with its own buyer bonuses! There are so many kinds you might get lost, but please check out the various CD shop pages!
特典のデザインは後日公開しますので、そちらもお楽しみに！
The bonus designs will be revealed later, so look forward to that as well!
ファーストアルバム「FBKINGDOM Blessing」の情報はこのあと21時30分オープンのアルバム特設サイトにてまとめて掲載しております！
Information on the 1st album "FBKINGDOM Blessing" will be compiled and published on the album special site opening tonight at 9:30 PM!
アルバムに関するハッシュタグは#DearFBKINGDOM！そのあと21時30分から予約開始となりますので、国民の皆様ぜひよろしくお願いいたします！
The hashtag for the album is #DearFBKINGDOM! Pre-orders will start right after at 9:30 PM, so citizens of the kingdom, your support means the world!